A city state was a self -sufficient area ruled by a king or a tyrant -
- the latter only a term for a ruler who conquered power
(often with some popular support) instead of inherited it.
The Greece of the time was also considerably larger than today and included parts of the present Turkey
and colonies along large parts of the Mediterranean.
At this time, a number of thinkers appeared who began to question the prevailing truths.
They no longer content themselves with trusting myths and gods tales
Without the help of reason to understand the world.
In the past, knowledge of the myths had been what made the people meaning and guidance in life.
Drought and illness, war and accident, birth and death - everything was due to the belief in the power and influence of the gods.
These myths would be managed and were not allowed to be questioned or changed.
The historians who recorded the fate of the people
began to refer to human decisions and natural circumstances
- It was no longer the gods that decided the fate of man, it was herself.
Eventually Greece developed into an economic and military superpower
with Athens as the dominant city state.
Here, culture and free debate flourished in a way that was unparalleled in the ancient world.
To this cultural center, thinkers sought from all of the Greek civilization
And now the city ended up in the philosophical eye -catching.
Old traditions and performances were questioned and abandoned - but what would come in its place?
How would one shape the new society and how would man know
Which way she was going to wander now when the gods no longer ruled?